<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mike Nichols</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Mike Nichols</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://c0psrul3.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zipari</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/zipari/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/zipari/</guid><description> Implemented comprehensive metrics and monitoring system with Prometheus to replace Sensu-based monitoring. Collected metrics from Cloudwatch, EC2 instances, Kubernetes, and Postgres databases to change the operations culture from re-active to pro-active. Developed Helm charts and EKS/Kubernetes platform design with CI/CD pipelines in both Gitlab and Jenkins. Managed business-critical internal systems, including GitLab, LDAP, OpenVPN, JIRA/Confluence. For fun, developed digital signage implementation for Dumbo office.</description></item><item><title>Generic Network Systems, LLC.</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/generic-network-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/generic-network-systems/</guid><description>Designed and implemented Elasticsearch (ELK) stack for log management and audit data collection for security, inventory and reports purposes. Team-member training for new-hires, junior-level peers, and cross-knowledge-domain admins. Worked to fulfill on-demand client/customer requests, while maintaining monitoring infrastructure and SLA goals for almost 200 clients and 1000+ hosts of mixed operating systems, including CentOS/RHEL 5,6,7; Oracle Solaris 10u8-11.3; Ubuntu 12.04-16.10; Debian 6,7; FreeBSD 10-11; and Windows Server 2012 (especially in cases where Active Directory was integrated).</description></item><item><title>Benchmark Education Company</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/benchmark-education-company/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/benchmark-education-company/</guid><description> Linux systems manager for LAMP stack and webapp troubleshooting. Designed release process and deployment processes. Implemented metrics and monitoring systems with Icinga/Nagios and Graphite AWS/Cloud infrastructure design, implementation, and maintenance Some website application development (PHP - Spiral Framework) Assisted migration from SVN to Git, as well as Git training.</description></item><item><title>INTERESTS and QUALIFICATIONS</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/qualifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/qualifications/</guid><description>Extensive management experience with BSD/UNIX and GNU/Linux operating systems, containerization (including Kubernetes, Docker, and Jails), DevOps automation, and Continuous Integration.
Created dev and test environments off different applications by provisioning k8s clusters on AWS using Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible, and Docker.
In depth knowledge of AWS cloud infrastructure, including EKS, and some exposure to Google Cloud.
One of my passions is metrics, monitoring, and security.</description></item><item><title>OBJECTIVES</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/objectives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/objectives/</guid><description> I’m looking to join a company which contributes back to the world, whether it be through contributions to non-profit organizations or open source projects.</description></item><item><title>PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE</title><link>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c0psrul3.github.io/resume/experience/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>